Guncha Chopra

guncha.chopra1501@gmail.com +91 981.830.7560 Janakpuri, New Delhi

PROFILE

Experienced professional with \sim 5 years of progressive experience in budgeting, financial reporting, and variance analysis and project management. Proven ability to evaluate business processes and provide recommendations to create value and improve efficiency. A confident, motivated professional with strong communication skills.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Budgeting & Forecasting
- Variance Analysis
- Liquidity Reporting

- Sales Analytics
- Month-end Close
- Process Automation
- Financial Reporting
- TM1
- MS Excel & PowerPoint

EXPERIENCE

HSBC Global Financial Centre, India

Manager, Finance Operations

July. 2018 – Present

- Support Business Controller with analysis of financial results to identify key business themes driving variances to projection.
- Prepare monthly and quarterly presentations to summarize business performance for management reviews.
- Conduct weekly and monthly calls with onshore partners to review the factors contributing to overall liquidity position.
- Prepare financial dashboards for Asset Liability Committee for decision making in the ALCO meeting.
- Responsible for troubleshooting across liquidity & funding reports. Aligning data from legacy systems to bridge the liquidity reporting gaps and ensure smooth transition from one system to another.
- Review and discuss changes in the regulatory guidelines with the policy team and implement the policy changes in the reporting process.
- Accomplishment: Recognized by Global Treasurer for managing ECB Liquidity Stress testing project.

Assistant Manager, ALM Reporting

March.2016 – June 2018

- Daily submission of reports monitoring liquidity position and additional related metrics of the division.
- Understanding the liquid asset buffer movement against net liquidity outflows, monthly balance sheet comparison and investigating unusual values and trends in liquidity reporting.
- Quality assurance for ALM reporting& automation of processes to reduce the turn-around-time of reporting.
- Accomplishment: Recognized as a strong performer consistently and received Spot on award.

RBS Global Financial services, India

Financial Analyst, Management Reporting

Nov. 2014 – Feb. 2016

- Preparing and analyzing management reports to support management reviews.
- Creating financial reports to identify risks and opportunities and communicating them to the business partners.
- Designing and implementing comprehensive KPIs to analyze growth drivers for its CIB business.
- Provide analysis focused on understanding actuals to onshore partners monthly. Present the analysis and address any questions related to the Month-end close.
- > Accomplishment: Simplification and standardization of Critical reports, thus ensuring high quality and efficient management reporting.

Ernst & Young, Global Shared Services

Lead audit associate, Audit Assurance Services

Nov. 2009 – Oct. 2012

- Reviewed Balance sheet and Profit and loss account for internal accuracy
- Prepared lead schedules with reference to trial balance and prior year workings
- Performed routine substantive procedures and control-based audit testing for clients
- Worked on various XBRL-based projects for financial information.
- Accomplishment: Recognized as a strong performer and awarded with extra miller award.

Internship Experience: Development Bank of Singapore, India

July - Oct. 2014

- Maintenance of the Loan Condition sheet for the borrower, financials, and risk profiling.
- Monthly comparison of offshore and onshore facility Interest O/s, Principal O/s, Secured and Unsecured portion with the mentioned collateral amount to the current month.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS

Cost and Management Accountant, ICWAI

Bachelors of Commerce, Gargi College, Delhi University

Achievement: Received an 'Award of Excellence' for the highest aggregate in annual examination of 2008 in B. Com.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

TM1, Risk Analyst tool, Microsoft Office – Access, Excel and PowerPoint, Khalix, XBRL